so far we have been powering everything using steam turbines
but now we got to the point where the steam pipes are too much of a mess
and the amount of turbines used is starting to get out of hand
as we have seen in previous episode
we had to do things that way due to cable power loss
but now that we work with 500 volts
the power loss is negligible
that means we can now start using longer cables
long enough to cover all of our base
but that leaves us with a new challenge
deciding which cable to use
while every material has different stats
the thing which might be trickier is deciding its thickness
that last choice only changes the maximum ampage
so to pick a proper size
we have to understand how many amps the cable is going to carry
this value is determined by two things
how much power can enter the cable
and how much can be drawn
in this example
we have a machine which can draw 2 amps
with a turbine that produces 1
since there is no way for 2 amps to be pushed in that cable
we can chip out and use a thin 1 amp cable
but if our generator was a transformer with an output of 4 amps
the limiting factor will become the 2 amps used by the electrolyzer
thus requiring a 2 amps cable
to be more precise
the electrolyzer doesn't really need the 2 amps
this value depends on many factors
all of these recipes are actually less than 1 amp
and if there is no cable loss we can use a 1 amp cable
however if there was a power fluctuation
the cable will have to carry some current spikes to refill the machine's internal buffer
thus melting
anyways in most of the cases
you will want to size the cable according to the power source
which is usually clearly stated
and if that amount is too high
you can use a cable diode to put a clear limit on how much current can flow in a section of cable
here we can see a 4 amp diode
ensuring that a 4 amp cable won't burn
also by limiting the power draw of this section
we ensure that we will have leftover power for our blast furnaces
and that could be one of the downsides of having a single main energy storage
we can only draw 1 amp for each battery
and we are going to power many machines at once
which could cause some nasty power spikes
this central node allows for an energy detector cover to optimize power usage by toggling less furnace and backup generator
by the way we are still producing our energy from steam
solar boilers are usually a great way of doing so
but this time we are instead using 4 railcraft boilers
powered by 2 advanced coke oven
fed by a single LV crop manager
this setup can work perpetually with no maintenance
and produces about 3 amps of HV power
let's do a quick recap
every cable has three values voltage amperage and loss
generator  push energy into the cables as packets of a fixed size
that size is the voltage
and there is a limit of how big of a packet a cable can carry
every time a packet is moved through a cable
it will lose a value equal to the cable loss
finally we have amperage
that value represents how many packets are moving simultaneously
到目前为止，我们一直使用蒸汽轮机为一切提供动力
但是现在我们已经到了蒸汽管道一团糟的地步
涡轮机的使用量开始失控
正如我们在前一集中看到的那样
由于电缆线损，我们不得不这样做
但现在我们用的是500伏特
能量损失可以忽略不计
这意味着我们现在可以开始使用更长的电缆
足够覆盖我们所有的基地
但这给我们带来了新的挑战
也就是决定使用哪种电缆
虽然每种材料都有不同的数据
更棘手的是决定它的厚度
厚度的选择只会改变最大电流
所以要选择合适的尺寸
我们必须了解电缆将承载多少安的电流
这个值是由两件事决定的
多少电量可以进入电缆
以及机器可以抽取多少
在这个例子中
我们有一台可以抽2A的机器
与产生1A的涡轮机
因为没有办法在该电缆中产生2A电流
我们可以转而使用细的1A电缆
但如果我们的发电机是输出为4A的变压器
限制因素将成为电解机使用的2A
因此需要2A的电缆
更准确地说
电解机并不是真的需要2A
这个值取决于许多因素
所有这些配方实际上都不到1A
如果没有电缆丢失，我们可以使用1A电缆
但是如果有能量波动
电缆必须能承载一些电流尖峰
来重新填充机器的内部缓冲区
导致电缆融化
无论如何，在大多数情况下
你只需要根据电源调整电缆的尺寸
这通常是明确说明的
如果电流太高
你可以使用电缆二极管来明确限制
一段电缆中可以流动的电流
这里我们可以看到一个4A二极管
确保4A电缆不会烧坏
通过限制这部分的用电
我们能确保高炉有剩余的电力
这可能是单一主储能的缺点之一
我们每个电池只能抽1A
我们将同时为许多机器提供动力
这可能会导致一些严重的用电峰值
这个中央节点允许通过使用能量检测覆盖板
启停高炉和备用发电机来优化电力使用
顺便说一句，我们还在用蒸汽产生能量
太阳能锅炉通常是生产蒸汽的正确选择
但这次我们使用了4台RC锅炉
由2个进阶焦炉提供燃料
由一个LV作物管理机提供原料
此设置无需维护即可永久工作
并产生大约3A HV
让我们快速总结一下
每根电缆都有三个数值：电压、电流和线损
发电机将能量作为固定尺寸的“包”输送到电缆中
能量“包”的大小是电压
电缆可以承载的“包”大小是有限制的
每次电“包”通过电缆移动时
它的大小将损失一个等于线损的值
最后是安培数/电流数
该值表示同时移动的“包”数量